In the previous video, we talked about activation but we never said what
在上一个视频中，我们谈到了激活，但从未说过
information we actually need to keep for an activation. That's the topic of this
我们实际上需要为激活保存的信息。这就是今天的主题
video. An activation record is all the information that's needed to manage the
录像带。激活记录是管理
execution of one procedure activation And often, this is also called a frame that
执行一个过程激活，这通常也称为帧，该帧
means exactly the same thing as activation record. These are just two names for the
与激活记录的含义完全相同。这只是两个名称
same thing. Now one interesting fact about procedure activations is that they have
一样的事。现在关于程序激活的一个有趣的事实是，他们有
more information in them than you might expect. So in particular, when a procedure
其中包含的信息比你想象的要多。所以特别是当一个程序
f calls a procedure g, the activation record for g will actually have
f调用过程g，则g的激活记录将实际具有
information not only about g but very frequently also about the calling function
不仅是关于g的信息，而且非常频繁地也是关于调用函数的信息
f. So typically the activation record for a procedure will contain a mixture of
f.因此，通常过程的激活记录将包含
information both about that procedure and about the procedure that called it. Now,
有关该过程和调用它的过程的信息。现在,
up this point, we haven't said why we need to keep information about activations at
到目前为止，我们还没有说明为什么需要将有关激活的信息保存在
all And the reason is that there is some state associated with this procedure
这一切的原因是，有一些状态与此过程相关联
activation that is needed on order to properly execute the procedure and we have
正确执行该过程所需的激活，我们有
to track that somewhere and that's the activation record is gonna be forced. It's
去某个地方追踪它，那就是激活记录将被强制。它是
gonna be the whole, the information needed to properly execute the procedure. So,
将是正确执行程序所需的全部信息。所以,
let's look at that in a little bit more detail. Let's consider this situation
让我们更详细地看一下这一点。让我们考虑一下这种情况
where a procedure F calls procedure G And what is going to happen so conceptually
其中过程F调用过程G，概念上会发生什么
what happens when f calls g is that f is suspended. F is going to stop Executing
当f调用g时会发生什么，那就是f被挂起了。F将停止执行
while g is running. So g is going to be using the processor and all the resources
而G正在运行。因此g将使用处理器和所有资源
of the machine. But when g completes, we wanna start executing f again, f is going
这台机器的。但是当g完成时，我们想要再次开始执行，
to resume. And so in between, while g is running, we have to save the state of the
重新开始。因此在这两者之间，当g运行时，我们必须保存
procedure activation of f somewhere so that we can resume it properly and that's
在某个地方激活f的过程，这样我们就可以正确地恢复它，那就是
again what the activation record is for, And so g's activation record Is going to
再次说明激活记录的用途，因此g的激活记录将
have to have information in it that will help us to complete the execution of g, so
必须包含帮助我们完成g的执行的信息，所以
there will be some inform ation about g that we just need in order to run g, But
将会有一些关于g的信息，我们只需要这些信息就可以运行g，但是
also, g's activation record is going to have to store whatever we need to be able
此外，g的激活记录将必须存储我们需要的任何内容
to resume the execution of procedure f. So let's work through an example. Here's one
来继续执行过程f，让我们通过一个例子来完成。这里有一个
of the programs that we looked at in the last video, and here is a design for a
我们在上一个视频中看过的程序，这是一个
concrete activation record for the procedure f. So we'll have one position
程序f的具体激活记录。所以我们有一个位置
for the results of f that will hold the return value after we finished execution
对于f的结果，它将在我们完成执行后保存返回值
of f. There will be a position here for the argument to f so is it, so fy takes
这里会有一个论点的位置，所以它是，所以fy取
one parameter so I only need one word here to hold the, the argument to the function.
一个参数，所以我在这里只需要一个词来保存，函数的自变量。
There will be a control link so a pointer to the previous or the caller's activation
将有一个控制链接，因此指向上一个或调用者激活的指针
and we'll also have a slot for the return address so the address in memory or the
我们还会有一个用于存放返回地址的槽，因此内存中的地址或
address of the instruction that we are supposed to jump to after the execution of
的执行后我们应该跳转到的指令地址。
f completes. So now let's just execute this program by hand and work out what the
F完成。现在让我们手动执行这个程序，并计算出
activation records will look like down the stack. So when the front program is first
激活记录将看起来像堆栈中的下一层。所以当前面的节目第一个
invoked, it will call main. There will be an activation record for main And we were
调用时，它将调用Main。将会有Main的激活记录，而我们
not gonna worry about that. We're just gonna focus on that. So there's some stuff
不会担心这个的。我们只会把重点放在这一点上。所以有一些东西
for main but we're not going to do to, to, to talk about that And then main is going
但是我们不会去，去，去讨论这个，然后Main就会去做，去
to call f, all right And so, when main calls f, an activation record will be
要调用f，好的，所以当main调用f时，激活记录将是
pushed onto the stack and we'll have four slots and or four fields for values. And
推送到堆栈上，我们将有四个槽和/或四个值字段。和
what we're going now while the first lines for the result well is just starting to
我们现在要做的是，而结果的第一行才刚刚开始
run if it's just beginning execution so there is nothing to put there at the
如果它刚刚开始执行，则运行，这样就没有什么可以放在
moment. That gets filled in when f returns. The second position will hold the
稍等片刻。它在f返回时被填充。第二个职位将持有
argument to f so that would be the number three. The third slot will hold the
参数赋给f，所以这就是数字3。第三个插槽将容纳
controlling so that's gonna point back. To the activation for main and the fourth
控制欲所以那会指向后面。去激活Main和Fourth
position will hold the return address and this is actually not completely trivial
位置将保存回邮地址，这实际上并不是完全无关紧要的
because f is called in multiple places. So if you look at the program, there's a
因为f在多个地方被调用。所以如果你看一下这个节目，你会发现
called f in main and there's a call to f inside of f itself. And so Depending on
在main中称为f，在f本身内部有一个对f的调用。所以这取决于
where the function is called from after that function completes with one or return
在该函数以1或返回完成后调用该函数的位置
to a different address. In the case of the main, when this called F completes we
寄到不同的地址。在Main的情况下，当这个调用F完成时，我们
wanna return to the. Whatever instructions comes after the called f which is just
想要回到。任何指令都在被调用的f之后，它只是
gonna be something that wraps up the execution program since it's the only exit
将会是结束执行程序的东西，因为它是唯一的出口
point of main inside of f. It's going to be the conclusion of the conditionals. So,
f内部的主点，它将是条件句的结论。所以,
this point double star here is going to be at whatever is left on the conditional
这里的点双星将在条件条件下剩下的任何位置
then the return from F. And so depending on what F is called from, we wanna return
然后是F的返回值，根据F是从什么地方调用的，我们想要返回
to one of two different places, okay? So, in this case F is being called from main
去两个不同的地方之一，好吗？因此，在本例中，F是从Main调用的
and so we'll put the single star address in that position of the activation record,
因此我们将把单星地址放在激活记录的那个位置，
All right? So then f is called the second time, the body of f executes and the
好的?因此，第二次调用f，执行f的主体，然后
argument three is not zero that's way we wined up calling f again but that means
参数3不是零，这就是我们再次调用f的方式，但这意味着
that another activation record will be pushed on to the stack that will also help
另一个激活记录将被推送到堆栈上，这也会有所帮助
for slots as an activation record for f (I probably should label these) so that's an
对于作为f的激活记录的插槽(我可能应该标记这些记录)，所以这是一个
activation of f, so it's also an activation of f. And what goes in this one
激活f，所以这也是f的激活。
well again the result doesn't have anything initially in it. The argument in
再说一遍，结果一开始没有任何内容。中的论点
this case would be two. The controlling in this case will point back to the previous
这个案子应该是两个。本例中的控件将指向上一个
activation of f and the return address in this case will be the point double star.
在这种情况下，f和返回地址的激活将是点双星。
So after two calls to f, this is what the stack will look like with this particular
因此，在两次调用f之后，这就是堆栈在这个特殊情况下的样子
activation record design. So, here is the same picture, just running a bit more
激活记录设计。所以，这是同样的图片，只是多放了一点
neatly, and there's one additional we want point out which is at this stack of
整齐地，我们还想指出一个额外的问题，那就是在这个堆栈中
activation records and let me. Delineate the activation records here Is not as
激活记录，让我来。此处描述的激活记录不是
extract as the kinds of stacks who were probably taught about in a data structures
提取为可能在数据结构中讲授的堆栈类型
class if you've had such a class. So here, there are distinct activation records on
如果你上过这样的课的话。在这里，有不同的激活记录
the stack and we treat them as such, in the Runtime system we'll treat them as
堆栈，我们就是这样对待它们的，在运行时系统中，我们会把它们当作
such But this is also like one gigantic array. All o f this Data is just laid out
但这也像是一个巨大的阵列。所有这些数据都是刚刚布置好的
in contiguous memory. These were all contiguous addresses and one is activation
在连续的记忆中。这些都是连续的地址，其中一个是激活
record here just follows on with the next address merely after the previous
这里的记录只是紧跟在前一个地址之后的下一个地址
activation record. And compiler is, compiler writer will often play tricks to
激活记录。而编译器就是，编译器编写者经常会耍花招
exploit the facts that these activations are adjacent to each other in memory and
利用这些激活在内存中彼此相邻的事实
we'll see one such potential trick in just a moment. To summarize some of the
稍后我们将看到这样一个潜在的把戏。总结一下一些
highlights of these examples so far, I wanna repeat the main is not very
这些例子的亮点到目前为止，我想重复的主要不是很多
interesting. So it has no argument or local variables and if results is never
有意思的。因此它没有参数或局部变量，并且如果结果从未
used And so while it does have an activation record, we're just not focusing
所以虽然它确实有激活记录，但我们没有把注意力集中在
on that and we're not concerning ourselves with what goes in at activation record.
关于这一点，我们并不关心激活记录中的内容。
We're just focusing on the activation record for f. Just be true this clear, the
我们只关注f的激活记录。请清楚地说，
start and double star that I use in the example, these are addresses in memory.
我在示例中使用的开始和双星，这些都是内存中的地址。
These are actual memory addresses and they refer to addresses of code. Those are the
这些是实际的内存地址，它们指的是代码地址。这些都是
addresses of the instructions that come after they call f because that's the place
调用f之后出现的指令的地址，因为这是
where f would return to. And finally, I want to stress that this really is only
f将返回的位置。最后，我想强调的是，这真的只是
one of many possible activation record designs. You can design a different
许多可能的激活记录设计之一。您可以设计不同的
activation record for f that has had different information that would work just
具有不同信息的f的激活记录
fine depending on the structure of the rest of the cogenerator in the runtime
很好，这取决于运行时协生成器的睡觉的结构
system. So, in particular many compilers don't use the controlling because they
系统。因此，特别是许多编译器不使用控件，因为它们
don't need inexpensive link to be able to find the calling or the activation record
不需要便宜的链接即可找到呼叫或激活记录
of the calling procedure and in fact, in your class project, the Khul compiler you
实际上，在您的类项目中，khul编译器
won't be using a control link Most. Activation records won't have the return
大多数情况下不会使用控制链接。激活记录将不会有退货
value on the activation record because it'd be more efficient and convenient to
值，因为这样会更有效、更方便地
return it in the register. All right, this is just one possible design and with and
把它放回收银机里。好的，这只是一种可能的设计
you could just design other activation records that will work just fine. The
您只需设计其他工作正常的激活记录即可。这个
important thing about the activation record is that it just have to have
关于激活记录的重要一点是，它只需要
sufficient information in it to e nable the generated code to properly execute the
其中有足够的信息使生成的代码能够正确执行
procedure that's being called And also to resume execution of the calling procedure.
过程，并恢复调用过程的执行。
So far, we've only looked at the procedure call for this activation record. We
到目前为止，我们只查看了此激活记录的过程调用。我们
haven't talked about what happens when activations return. So let's consider what
我还没有谈到激活恢复后会发生什么。那么让我们考虑一下
happens in our example after the second called f that this one this activation
在我们的示例中，在名为f的第二个激活之后发生
down here returns. So what's going to happen is we're going to make the caller,
从这里下来就回来了。所以接下来要做的是，我们要给来电者打电话，
the current activation so it'll actually become the top of the stack so I'll have this big fat
当前的激活，所以它实际上会成为堆栈的顶部，所以我会有一个很大的胖子
green error here indicated that this is now the current activation this one up
这里的绿色错误表示这是当前的激活状态
here. Okay? So, this is the call, this is the what was the caller and is now going
这里。好吧?所以，这就是电话，这就是以前的呼叫者，现在
to resume executing. And the interesting thing here is to note that, like I said
恢复执行。有趣的是要注意到，就像我说的
before, this isn't as abstract as a stack in a data structures course. So while we
以前，这不像数据结构课程中的堆栈那样抽象。所以当我们
have restored this as the active procedure, this data down here, this, this
我把这个恢复为活动的程序，这个下面的这个数据，这个，这个
activation that was running is still there in memory. And in fact we can go and look
正在运行的激活仍在内存中。事实上我们可以去看看
at it if we want to. And the way I set this example up in fact we need to because
如果我们想的话。我建立这个例子的方式实际上是我们需要的，因为
the results of the procedure that we called is now stored here. In the first
我们调用的过程的结果现在存储在这里。在第一个
word of this activation, All right, So when f begins executing again, is going to
这个激活的词，好的，所以当f再次开始执行时，
have to look up that result in order to know what the result was of the procedure
我必须查一下结果才能知道这个过程的结果是什么
levels called. So the advantage of placing the return value in the first position in
称为关卡。因此将返回值放在
the frame that the call can find it at a fix offset from its own frame. Let's back
调用可以在其自身帧的固定偏移量处找到它的帧。我们回去吧
up and just see that so here when the second call to f has returned and the, the
在这里，当对f的第二个调用返回时，
first call here has resumed executing this call, the code for this call will know
此处的第一个调用已恢复执行此调用，此调用的代码将知道
that the science of this activation record is four. There are four words in this
这张激活记录的科学值是4。这里面有四个字
activation record and so they can find the result to the procedure that it called in
激活记录，因此他们可以找到它调用的过程的结果
the four + one position and five words passed the top of the frame. So in
四加一的位置和五个字通过了框架的顶部。所以在
particular, they'll be able to find this where in memory and even though this has
具体地说，他们将能够在内存中的什么地方找到它，即使它有
been popped out of the stack as I said before, that data is still there at least
已经从堆栈中弹出，该数据至少还在那里
until another procedure is called. And so, if we immediately read the result of the
直到调用另一个过程。所以，如果我们立即读到
function call after we return from the function, we'll be able to pick up that
函数调用在我们从函数返回之后，我们将能够拾取它
result and then use it in the continuation of the execution of the call in procedure.
结果，然后在过程中继续执行调用时使用它。
And once again, I just wanna stress, I know this is a couple of times, but it's
再说一次，我只想强调一下，我知道这是几次了，但是
very important that there's absolutely nothing magic about this organization. We
非常重要的是，这个组织绝对没有什么神奇之处。我们
could rearrange the order of elements in the frame. We could divide the
可以重新排列框架中元素的顺序。我们可以平分
responsibility between the caller and the calling differently And really the only
呼叫者和呼叫者之间的责任不同，而且实际上是唯一的
metric here is that one organization is better than another if it results and
这里的衡量标准是一个组织比另一个组织更好，如果结果是
faster code or in a simpler code generator And I know I also mentioned this before but
更快的代码或更简单的代码生成器，我知道我之前也提到过这一点，但是
it's also an important point in a production compiler we would produce much
在生产编译器中，这也是一个重要的点，我们会产生很多
of the frame contents as possible in registers And in particular, there would
寄存器中尽可能多的帧内容，尤其是
be a effort to pass the method results and the method arguments in registers because
努力在寄存器中传递方法结果和方法参数，因为
those are excess so frequently. Finally to some up our discussion of activations and
这些都是经常出现的过剩现象。最后，让我们来总结一下我们对激活和
activation records, the issue is that the compiler has to determine at compile time,
激活记录，问题是编译器必须在编译时确定，
okay so this happens statically. The layout of the activation record and also
好的，这是静态发生的。激活记录的布局，还
has to generate code that correctly accesses the locations in that activation
必须生成正确访问该激活中的位置的代码
record. And what does this mean, this mean that the activation record layout and the
录音。这意味着，激活记录布局和
code generator have to be designed together. Okay. So, you can't just assign
代码生成器必须一起设计。好吧。所以，你不能就这么把
your code generator and then figure out later what your activation record layout
您的代码生成器，然后稍后确定您的激活记录布局是什么
is gonna be or vice versa, This two things needs to designed together because they
或者反之亦然，这两个东西需要一起设计，因为它们
depend on each other.
相互依赖。